<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>2021, I am ready</title>
    <link href="/2021-i-am-ready.html"/>
    <url>/2021-i-am-ready.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2020 is an extraordinary year. During this year, I have experienced a lot, grew a lot, and learned a lot. In the face of the sudden outbreak of COVID-19 pandemic, it changed everything suddenly. During this period we were all forced to take “cloud lessons” and I was also forced to take classes at home. At the beginning, there were a lot of things that I was not used to, but it gradually became numb, and did not care that much. At the same time during the pandemic I also learned a new instrument, the violin. Another important event that changed the direction of my life was that in July I got the offer from the Uppsala University. This also mean that I will start a new life in Uppsala. In September, I came to this strange city alone. A city with no friends, no relatives, and no reliance is here to start my new life. I learned that how to reads alone, study alone, think alone, cook alone, and live alone. Perhaps that is what growth up mean. Time rushed into December, and a short semester passed. I still do not regret my decision. In life, I think is should go around and see more, learn more about the new environment, and open horizons about the world.</p><p>On New Year’s Eve, I am alone in the dark and empty room to write this blog. I am not a traditional person or person who has a sense of ritual. Although 2020 is indeed extraordinary, I hope that this new year 2021 will also have new hope, new motivation, and new meaning. Time flies really fast, and my 21 years have passed like in a moment. We all say goodbye to the people and things in the past at that crossroad. While I looking back now, it only myself is around. The journey of life is so far, I hope to meet a better myself in the front.</p><p>I have set a few goals in this new year.</p><ul><li>Start the four theoretical mechanics and understand them<ul><li>Quantum mechanics</li><li>Electrodynamics</li><li>Theoretical Mechanics</li><li>Statistical Mechanics</li></ul></li><li>Participate the college physics competitions</li><li>As in previous years, I still need to improve my English</li><li>the world is so big I want to see and travel around especially China</li><li>Better biological clock, better time management, better character</li><li>Stay away from social media</li><li>I want to read more books this year and learn more.</li><li>Improved my violin skills</li></ul><p>Don’t forget to love yourself in this strange city.</p><hr><p>2020是一个不平凡的一年，在这一年经历了很多，成长了很多，见识了很多。面对突如其来的新冠肺炎，我们都防不胜防。在这期间我们都被迫上“云课”，我也被迫在家上课。刚开始有很多东西不习惯，但慢慢的也就麻木了，无所谓了。同时我疫情期间也学习了一件新的乐器，小提琴。另外一个改变我人生方向的重大事件是在七月份我拿到了乌普萨拉物理系的录取通知书。这也将意味着我要在乌普萨拉开启新的生活。今年的九月我孤身一人来到这陌生的城市。无朋友，无亲戚，无依靠的城市这来开启我的新生活。我学会了一个人看书，一个人学习，一个人思考，一个人做饭，一个人生活。或许那就是成长把。时间匆匆忙忙到了十二月，短短的一个大学学期就过去了。我仍然没有后悔当初的决定。人生把，我觉得就应该多去看看，多去了解一下新的环境，开开自己的眼界。</p><p>新年前夕我一个人在乎黑忽暗,空虚的房间写这篇文章。我并不是一个传统的，有仪式感的人。虽然2020的确不平凡但我希望这这新的一年也有新的希望，新动力，以及新的意义。时间过得真的很快，匆匆忙忙我的21年如同一刹那间度过。曾经的人，曾经的事我们都在那十字路口里告别。如今回过头来,周围只剩我自己。人生路程如此遥远，希望在前面遇见更好的自己。</p><p>在这新的一年里我立下几个目标。</p><ul><li>开始四大力学，以及了解他们<ul><li>量子力学</li><li>电动力学</li><li>理论力学</li><li>统计力学</li></ul></li><li>参加大学物理比赛</li><li>像往年一样，我英语还是需要有待提高</li><li>我想回中国看看，世界那么大我想去看看</li><li>更好的生物钟，更好的时间管理，更好的人品</li><li>远离社交媒体</li><li>有时候我发现我读的书很少，我想在这一年内读多些书。</li><li>提高的我小提琴的技巧</li></ul><p>在这陌生的城市别忘了爱自己。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Life</tag>
      
      <tag>New year</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Stay focused, stay in flow</title>
    <link href="/stay-focused-stay-in-flow.html"/>
    <url>/stay-focused-stay-in-flow.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Life</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>My daily planning &amp; time management</title>
    <link href="/my-daily-planning-time-management.html"/>
    <url>/my-daily-planning-time-management.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>尽量写完！</p><h2 id="Background"><a href="#Background" class="headerlink" title="Background"></a>Background</h2><h3 id="The-concept-of-time-is-important"><a href="#The-concept-of-time-is-important" class="headerlink" title="The concept of time is  important"></a>The concept of time is  important</h3><p>有时候我意识到人这一生很短暂，有很多事情我们都来不及做。虽然每个人拥有的时间是一样，毕竟每个人都以小小小于光速运动着。那么真正能改变一个人的时间就是做事情的效率以及合理的安排。 简单来说我们管理时间的目的就是为了提高时间的利用效率 它能够延长我们生命的长度。</p><p>我本并不是一个高度自律的人， 但我想通过这样的方式去改变我自己。</p><h3 id="Self-reflection"><a href="#Self-reflection" class="headerlink" title="Self-reflection"></a>Self-reflection</h3><p>一下是我个人总结的一些小经验</p><h2 id="Daily-planning"><a href="#Daily-planning" class="headerlink" title="Daily planning"></a>Daily planning</h2><hr><center><p> <b>Morgonspass</b> </p>时间可控，心情放松且愉悦，不影响早睡。</center><hr><p><strong>04:00</strong> <em>Wake up</em></p><p><strong>04:00-04:30</strong> <em>Morning exercise</em></p><p>—Wake up the body—</p><p>早晨起床的时候，身体通常还处于僵硬、施展不开的状态，最自然的唤醒机制就是“伸懒腰”。但我们要采取的是更进一步地唤醒整个身体，比如：做运动、冥想、瑜伽、做早餐等。</p><p><strong>04:30-05:15</strong> <em>Writing blog, planning and reflection</em></p><blockquote><p>The unexamined life is not worth living. -Sokrates</p></blockquote><p>Indeed, understanding reflection can make oneself stronger. At the beginning of a new day, our mentality will be more peaceful, and we will be more rational when thinking and reflecting on things. Therefore, there will be a fairer and calmer attitude to reflect on what happened yesterday. This makes it easier for us to find what needs to be corrected and improved.</p><p>—Start the brain—</p><p>简单的规划：</p><ol><li>写晨间日记。 晨间日记就是早上写的日记，主要记录前一天发生的值得记录的事情，计划新一天的生活</li><li>写当天计划。整理清单列表，blockytime</li><li>写博客。</li></ol><p><strong>05:15-05:45</strong> <em>Out and walk</em><br>Just a short walk to freshen up. (optional)<br>我估计你应该会比较累，出去呼吸一下新鲜空气吧！</p><p><strong>06:00-07:30</strong> <em>Study 1.5h</em><br>现在是学习的时候了！</p><p><strong>7:30-7:45</strong> <em>Breakfast</em></p><p>Preferably a porridge with protein drink, eg milk or soy drink. As well as a fruit !!</p><p><strong>8:00-12:00</strong> <em>Study 4h</em></p><p>Time to study</p><hr><center><p> <b>Dagspass</b> </p>高效</center><hr><p><strong>12:00-13:00</strong> <em>Foodtime and lunchbreak</em></p><p>I have no choice with that time for lunch. If it is a regular lecture day, I am free from 12:00 to 13:00, which is then suitable for lunch and lunch puash.</p><p><strong>13:00-13:30</strong> <em>Take naps</em></p><p>Jag har prövat andra tillfället att ta en tupplur på eftermiddagen. Den optimala tiden tycker jag är mellan 13:00-13:30. Om det är senare än det så blir jag alldes förtrött då kommer jag inte hålla den i tid. Ibland så händer det att jag ta en förlång tupplur typ. 1h30min. Det leder till att jag inte kan sömna i kvällen.</p><p>Oavsett så tycker jag tt ta en kort tupplur är en bra återhämtning för dagen. Särskilt för mig som vakna tidigt på dagen. Om det i så fall att du missa den tiden så rekommedera jag att inte gör det på annnan tillfället. Du kan istället ta en kopp av kaffe eller likande.</p><p>中午我们要有午睡时间，午睡可以帮助我们快速回复精力。良好的精力是我们保持高效的基础，条件允许的尽量都要午睡。时间建议不要超过30分钟，因为一旦超过，很容易陷入深度睡眠，当你醒来后会更加的犯困。</p><p><strong>13:30-17:15</strong> 4h.</p><p>study</p><p><strong>17:15-18:00</strong> <em>Sports / Reading / Violin</em></p><p>Jag vill gärna har en arobisk träning varanan dag. I den bästa fall så är det varje dag. Det enda sport jag gillar mest om är ju att cykal och jogga. Jogga minst 5km. Hittis har jag ingen bra optimal till hur mycket jag måste cykla.</p><p>Om inte så vill jag har den tiden till att läsa eller praticera violin!</p><p><strong>18:00-19:00</strong> <em>Other</em></p><p>Here you have the time for a few other things. Very important and make good use of it !!</p><hr><center><p> <b>Kvällspass</b> </p>时间可控，心情放松且愉悦，不影响早睡。</center><hr><p><strong>19:00-19:30</strong> | <em>Foodtime and short break</em> |</p><p>Den tiden är då till kvällmat. Jag brukar bara laga mat på kväll. Så tiden kommer varierar lite då och då. Genomsnitt behöver jag 1h och lite mer till att laga mat.</p><p><strong>19:30-21:30</strong> 2h<br>Om det är för mycket föreläsning så uttnyttja den tiden till studerade. Om inte annars FREEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEEE!</p><p><strong>21:30</strong> <em>Prepare to bedtime</em><br>For the last half hour, I want it to the shower and toothbrushing.</p><p>As well as absolutely the most important, <strong><em>mediation</em></strong> or any way you can relax, or reduce stress. !! Very important !!</p><p>Another thing I experienced where it can interfere with my sleep was the telephone. Avoid the phone 30 minutes before going to bed. It’s important !!<br><strong>22:00</strong> | <em>Bedtime and goodnight</em> |</p><p>Turn off the lights and sleep. Going to bed early is the basis for you to get up early the next day. Sleeping at a fixed time every day helps to adjust the biological clock, to ensure that you have a better state to face the challenges of the next day, so that your mind is calm, creative and efficient.</p><h2 id="Sum-Up"><a href="#Sum-Up" class="headerlink" title="Sum Up"></a>Sum Up</h2><ul><li>Minimal 6 timmar sömn och optimal 7.5h</li><li>Gärna en varm drick innan jag lägger mig</li><li>Försök meditera minst en gång per dag</li><li>Motionera minst 4 ggr per veckan</li><li>Studera 8h</li></ul><h2 id="3-sorted-of-Time"><a href="#3-sorted-of-Time" class="headerlink" title="3 sorted of Time"></a>3 sorted of Time</h2><p>简单讲述这三种时间以及在这时间段我都想达到什么样的目的！</p><h3 id="Whole-piece-of-time"><a href="#Whole-piece-of-time" class="headerlink" title="Whole piece of time"></a>Whole piece of time</h3><h3 id="Fragments-of-time"><a href="#Fragments-of-time" class="headerlink" title="Fragments of time"></a>Fragments of time</h3><p>Use fragmented time to create miracles</p><h3 id="“Dark-time”"><a href="#“Dark-time”" class="headerlink" title="“Dark time”"></a>“Dark time”</h3><marquee>I wanna scroll with it, baby!</marquee><h2 id="Excellent-app"><a href="#Excellent-app" class="headerlink" title="Excellent app"></a>Excellent app</h2><p><a href="https://tide.fm/en_US/">Tide </a> - Sleep. Focus. Relax. Breath.</p><p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/blockytime/id1086617993">BlockyTime</a> - A simple time logger no need to tap Start/Stop.<br><a href="https://todo.microsoft.com/tasks/sv-se">Microsoft To Do</a> - Focus, from work to play<br><a href="https://www.focustodo.cn/">Focus To-Do</a> - Be focused and make things easier.</p><p>vetenskaplig förklarining<br>planer’<br><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_management">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_management</a><br>这是一句话<sup id="fnref:1" class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote"><span class="hint--top hint--rounded" aria-label="hejed">[1]</span></a></sup></p><section class="footnotes"><div class="footnote-list"><ol><li><span id="fn:1" class="footnote-text"><span>hejed<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref"> ↩</a></span></span></li></ol></div></section>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Life</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Funktionsteorin</title>
    <link href="/funktionsteorin.html"/>
    <url>/funktionsteorin.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Bakgrund"><a href="#Bakgrund" class="headerlink" title="Bakgrund"></a>Bakgrund</h2><p>Funktionsteorin så kallas även komplexa analys. Här är mina anteckningar från boken funktionsteorin av Frank Wikström. Det var en riktigt spännande bok som guida dig genom harmonisk analys och komplexa analys inom matematiken. Här kommer jag inte skriva härledning till satserna utan hänvisas jag till boken. Notera att även författare har inte hellre härledat strikt bevis för de mesta satser pga det är för tekniksk och komplex.<br><img src="/img/proof.jpg" alt=""></p><h2 id="1-Komplexa-funktioner"><a href="#1-Komplexa-funktioner" class="headerlink" title="1. Komplexa funktioner"></a>1. Komplexa funktioner</h2><p>Innan vi går vidare till derivator skall vi sätta ett definetion om gränsvärde för komlexa funktion. gränsvärde för komplexa funktioner har ungefär exakt samma pricip som den reellla funktion.</p><div class="note note-danger">            <p>Anta att $f$ är en komplexvärd funktion som är definera på någon omgivning av punkten $z = a$. Så gäller gränsvärde för komplexvärd funktion</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\lim_{z \to a}f(z) = L</script><p>Om det finns till varje $\epsilon &gt; 0$ finns ett $\delta &gt; 0$ sådana att</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">|f(z)-L| < \delta</script><p>för alla z med 0 &lt; $|z-a|&lt;\delta$</p>          </div><p>De vanöiga relltvärdes gränsvärde räknelagar gäller även sammma för komplexvärda funktioner. Alltså</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">P_\omega={n_\omega\over 2}\hbar\omega\,{1+R\over 1-v^2}\int\limits_{-1}^{1}dx\,(x-v)|x-v|,</script><h2 id="2-Elementara-funktioner"><a href="#2-Elementara-funktioner" class="headerlink" title="2. Elementära funktioner"></a>2. Elementära funktioner</h2><h3 id="Komplex-plynom"><a href="#Komplex-plynom" class="headerlink" title="Komplex plynom"></a>Komplex plynom</h3><h2 id="3-Komplex-integralkalkyl"><a href="#3-Komplex-integralkalkyl" class="headerlink" title="3. Komplex integralkalkyl"></a>3. Komplex integralkalkyl</h2><h2 id="4-Talfoljder-och-rekursionsekvationer"><a href="#4-Talfoljder-och-rekursionsekvationer" class="headerlink" title="4. Talföljder och rekursionsekvationer"></a>4. Talföljder och rekursionsekvationer</h2><h2 id="5-Serier"><a href="#5-Serier" class="headerlink" title="5. Serier"></a>5. Serier</h2><h2 id="6-Funktionsfoljder-och-funktionsserier"><a href="#6-Funktionsfoljder-och-funktionsserier" class="headerlink" title="6. Funktionsföljder och funktionsserier"></a>6. Funktionsföljder och funktionsserier</h2><h2 id="7-Fourierserier"><a href="#7-Fourierserier" class="headerlink" title="7. Fourierserier"></a>7. Fourierserier</h2><h2 id="8-Potensserier-och-analytiska-funktioner"><a href="#8-Potensserier-och-analytiska-funktioner" class="headerlink" title="8. Potensserier och analytiska funktioner"></a>8. Potensserier och analytiska funktioner</h2><h2 id="9-Singulariteter"><a href="#9-Singulariteter" class="headerlink" title="9. Singulariteter"></a>9. Singulariteter</h2><h2 id="10-Residykalkyl"><a href="#10-Residykalkyl" class="headerlink" title="10. Residykalkyl"></a>10. Residykalkyl</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Mathematics</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>What is the meaning of self-control?</title>
    <link href="/what-is-the-meaning-of-self-control.html"/>
    <url>/what-is-the-meaning-of-self-control.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>life</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Who am I? where I come from? where I want to go?</title>
    <link href="/who-am-i-where-i-come-from-where-i-want-to-go.html"/>
    <url>/who-am-i-where-i-come-from-where-i-want-to-go.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Who-am-I"><a href="#Who-am-I" class="headerlink" title="Who am I ?"></a>Who am I ?</h3><blockquote><p>“knowing yourself is the beginning of all wisdom.” -Aristotle</p><p>“knowing other is wisdom knowing the self is enlightenment” -Lao Tzu</p></blockquote><p>More than two thousand years ago, some people already began to think about self-consciousness. Aristoteles(384–322 BC) and Lao Tzu (600 BC) were the most famous ideologists and philosophers at the same period. The thing which surprised me is Lao Tzu came from Ancient China, meanwhile Aristoteles was från Ancient Greece and they both realized the importance of self-identity. Since these two independently developed civilizations can have such the same ideas. It really surprised me.  This kind of wisdom may not be truly understood by many people in today’s society. What I believe people nowadays pursue more material life than spirit of life.</p><h3 id="Where-I-come-from"><a href="#Where-I-come-from" class="headerlink" title="Where I come from?"></a>Where I come from?</h3><p>I know that is stupid quation. Everyone knows what themselves come from. Many people will say I am coming from some country or maybe they can specify where in the country in which city and road and so on. But do they really know where they </p><h3 id="Where-I-want-to-go"><a href="#Where-I-want-to-go" class="headerlink" title="Where I want to go?"></a>Where I want to go?</h3><blockquote><p>“I come from the great Tang dynasty of the east land and I’m going to pilgrim the budda for lection.” -Tang Sanzang</p></blockquote><p>This quote is coming from the chinese novel “Journey to the West”, it is one of the four great classical novels of chinese literature. This novel was published in the 16th century during the Ming dynasty and talked about the story of Tang Sanzang and his apprentices Sun Wukong, Zhu Bajie and Sha Wujing and going to the west to learn the scripture. Later it adapted from a novel into a TV series. As a child this was one of my favourite TV serier. I am atheist but this story really impacted me a lot.</p><p>This sentence is difficult to express its essence in other languages than chinese. It it little werid when I read it in english.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>life</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why I chose physics, Especially theoretical physics?</title>
    <link href="/why-i-chose-physics-especially-theoretical-physics.html"/>
    <url>/why-i-chose-physics-especially-theoretical-physics.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="First-inspiration-about-physics"><a href="#First-inspiration-about-physics" class="headerlink" title="First inspiration about physics"></a>First inspiration about physics</h3><p>The first memory that I actually know about the concept physics is at junior high school. To be honest, in the three year I don’t even know that I had a physics teacher but this did not make me lose my interest in physics.</p><p>When I was in second grade at junior high school I readed “The Quantum World” by Kenneth W. Ford. This book makes me think about physics and what is the fundamental of this universe(Sorry Hawking, your book “brief history of time” was not inspiring enough). In this book, I was the first time I really realized how fascinating and beautiful this universe is. In that moment I also realized how ignorable we are to compare the whole universe. The main reason I like physics is it makes me think and be curious all the time. From that day I decided to work with physics like “quantum” stuff or “particle” stuff that even I did not really know what this is. I never was a genius in physics or something. Maybe in my age when I was a child that Albert Einstein already began to think about the universe and I was the little poor boy sitting down in the sandpit and playing in the sand.</p><h3 id="I-want-more-challenge-and-more-physics"><a href="#I-want-more-challenge-and-more-physics" class="headerlink" title="I want more challenge and more physics"></a>I want more challenge and more physics</h3><p>When I was in the third year of junior high school, I was confused about choosing high school. Most of the people in my class choose a high school near home. In this case, I was the special case, I want to leave home, leave from my parents. I am very lucky and met my SYV or school counselor. She was kind and helped me a lot with how to choose high school. So far I am still very grateful to her. Without her I may not be here, my physics passion may be gone, who knows. Finally, I had a choice for my high school, Polhemskolan at Lund, with orientation gift education in physics. Actually, I had no idea what this meant, but what I knew is my high school would not be bored and I will meet a lot of people with the same passion as me.</p><p>That summer I was nervous and waiting for my admission to high school. The day before I could not fall asleep. I woke up early in the morning and updated the admissions website time and time until they uploaded admission notices. At that moment, I am happy and proud of myself. I came in Polhemskolan at Lund.</p><h3 id="Polhemskolan-another-inspiring-place"><a href="#Polhemskolan-another-inspiring-place" class="headerlink" title="Polhemskolan, another inspiring place"></a>Polhemskolan, another inspiring place</h3><p><img src="/img/polhemc.jpg" alt=""><br>At Polhemskolan I learned a lot. I had a nice three year there. There I got the elementary knowledge of math and physics. We had study visits e.g. nuclear power at Barsebäck, MAX IV Laboratory,  European Spallation Source (and CERN). During the education, we also had the opportunity to take a step at university. We had many lectures from Lund University and we did laboratory work at Lund University. In that way, my perspective on the physical world increased.</p><p>It turned out that I was very bad at study physics when I started in high school. I remembered that I stuck to the concept acceleration for several weeks before I fully understood it. It is similar to other concepts like energy conservation and other basic physics concepts.  Which is really ridiculous. Sometimes I was so sad and frustrated but I never gave up. No matter how frustrated I was, my physics passion never went away. A quotes from Lao Tzu “ The journey of a thousand miles begins with one step.” gave me a lot of motivation. Sometimes you can not reach the goal directly. You must do it step by step. That makes me enjoy physics in another way.</p><blockquote><p>“People who knows how to study is inferior to people who likes studying; people who likes studying is inferior to people who takes studying as joy.” - Konfucius</p></blockquote><p>It’s interesting for me to think about physics, but the process of learning physics makes me feel more fulfilled.</p><p> I think the most important thing I actually learned from polhem was my learning ability. Another advantage of that education was that you can start reading courses at the university level already in high school.</p><h3 id="Mathematics-is-my-favorite-dessert"><a href="#Mathematics-is-my-favorite-dessert" class="headerlink" title="Mathematics is my favorite dessert"></a>Mathematics is my favorite dessert</h3><p>从我记事起我觉得我的数学一直都很不错。至少我觉得数学这科目在学校中我觉得是最简单的。虽然我并没有得过什么重大的奖但也是一种喜好吧。</p><p>在高二的时候我对于数学的认知有了天翻付地的变化。有时候我觉得我之前我学的数学并不是真正的数学而是‘算数’。在某种意义上来说，我懂的如何去计算一道题，但我几乎好像从来都没刨根问底的去想这背后的意义是什么。我记得那一年我第一次接触到大学数学，微积分。那一年也是我数学的一次考试未及格。</p><p>有一次考试对我印象很深刻。那是一门muntan，主要就用用语言去表达这道题的解。那一天我心有成足的去考试，一般大概也就是10分钟。可结果是我和那教授足足坐在那讲了45分钟。从那开始我才认识到我是那么的愚昧与无知。我非常感谢那位教授，是他让我见识到我在数学大厦目前我是多么的弱小。同时也让我看到了数学的不同的角度。</p><p>从那以后我就抱了以往不同的心态，以及严谨的态度去学数学，真正意义上的数学。有时候我也曾问过我自己学数学有什么用。其实也没什么用，就像吃甜点那样。爱数学就觉得他好吃，好玩。</p><h3 id="I-don’t-know-what-theoretical-physicist-means-but-it-sound-fun"><a href="#I-don’t-know-what-theoretical-physicist-means-but-it-sound-fun" class="headerlink" title="I don’t know what theoretical physicist means but it sound fun"></a>I don’t know what theoretical physicist means but it sound fun</h3><p>说我懂物理其实也不然。懂的也只是一知半解。我了解理论物理学家大多数要不然就是书上或者网上。在现实生活当中我并没有认识过一名真正的理论物理学家。甚至连物理学家到底真正在做什么都是一头雾水。有时候看书的时候觉得那些理论物理学家，比如爱因斯坦，霍金，费曼等人都很酷。所以也就励志的想成为一名理论物理学家。</p><p>其实理论物理学家</p><h3 id="What-I-think-about-real-physics-v-s-popular-physics"><a href="#What-I-think-about-real-physics-v-s-popular-physics" class="headerlink" title="What I think about real physics v.s. popular physics"></a>What I think about real physics v.s. popular physics</h3><p>It was a interesting sentence that I found on the internet. “Nature magazine’s thickening speed has exceeded the speed of light, but this does not violate the special theory of relativity, because it does not convey any information.” What I think, that makes sense. The more physics I read and know, the more I think that popular science is a fairy tale in the physical world.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Life</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Physics</tag>
      
      <tag>Life</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>What do I expect to learn during the three years at university</title>
    <link href="/what-do-i-expect-to-learn-during-the-three-years-at-university.html"/>
    <url>/what-do-i-expect-to-learn-during-the-three-years-at-university.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A semester has passed when I write this article. </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>life</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>blog</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Experimental determination of the maximal lyapunov exponent of the magnetic pendulum</title>
    <link href="/experimental-determination-of-the-maximal-lyapunov-exponent-of-the-magnetic-pendulum.html"/>
    <url>/experimental-determination-of-the-maximal-lyapunov-exponent-of-the-magnetic-pendulum.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="note note-primary">            <p><strong>Abstract:</strong></p><p>The magnetic pendulum has a simple structure but a complex chaotic behaviour. Since a system has a positive maximal lyapunov exponent is strong indicates that system is chaotic. The studies of magnetic pendulum have been mathematically and numerically understood. Unfortunately, it is still lack of experimental examination of the lyapunov exponent of magnetic pendulum due the extreme and sensitive requirement. In this project is studied about the maximal lyapunov of magnetic pendulum experimentally. The study is not extensive and specifics for the chaotic behavior of magnetic pendulum. However, the result are showed the magnetic pendulum has a positive maximal lyapunov exponent about 28 1/s with a given parameter. Which is strong indicates that magnetic pendulum has a chaotic behaviour.</p>          </div><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\ddot{x}+\frac{b}{m}\dot{x} + \frac{g}{L}x + \frac{1}{m}\sum_{i=1}^{n}\frac{k_i}{(\sqrt{(x_i-x)^2+(y_i-y)^2+h^2})^3}(x-x_i)=0\\</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\ddot{y}+\frac{b}{m}\dot{y} + \frac{g}{L}y + \frac{1}{m}\sum_{i=1}^{n}\frac{k_i}{({\sqrt{(x_i-x)^2+(y_i-y)^2+h^2}})^3}(y-y_i)=0</script>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Physics</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Physics</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>GitHub + LaTeX make more efficient for writing and collaboration</title>
    <link href="/github-latex-make-more-efficient-for-writing-and-collaboration.html"/>
    <url>/github-latex-make-more-efficient-for-writing-and-collaboration.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>之前一直有一个问题困扰着我，就是如何多人写LaTeX。 我咨询过一个我的朋友他告诉我说Git是一个解决方案。我曾经尝试过Git很多次但都失败了，主要还是因为毕竟难入门。直到大概几个星期前，我们小组要用LaTeX写一篇论文。这我又想起我朋友的方案（其实我不想花钱在overleaf上），尝试用Git协助多人编辑。由于刚开始的时候并不是很懂，如何操作等。这篇文章是我一些个人总结，以及避免一些无必要的弯路。现在我还并没有完全掌握Git，在学习中。。</p><h2 id="Preparations"><a href="#Preparations" class="headerlink" title="Preparations"></a>Preparations</h2><p>You need to prepare two things on your computer</p><ul><li>Git</li><li>GitHub</li></ul><p><img src="/img/gitgithub.jpg" width=400 height=200 /></p><hr><p style="text-align:center;font-size:1.5em;font-weight: bold;">Let's GO!!</p><hr><h2 id="Git"><a href="#Git" class="headerlink" title="Git"></a>Git</h2><h3 id="What-is-Git-and-what-are-the-benefits-of-Git"><a href="#What-is-Git-and-what-are-the-benefits-of-Git" class="headerlink" title="What is Git and what are the benefits of Git?"></a>What is Git and what are the benefits of Git?</h3><p>Git är ett system för versionshantering främst tänkt att användas för programkod. Kortfattat är Git ett verktyg för att samarbeta kring kod som gör det möjligt att hantera ändringar och historik.</p><h3 id="Install-Git"><a href="#Install-Git" class="headerlink" title="Install Git"></a>Install Git</h3><p>For many novices, installing Git is not an easy task. On Linux, you only need to execute this command in the terminal.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ sudo apt-get install git<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>Emm, it doesn’t seem to be that difficult.</p><h3 id="Have-fun-with-Git"><a href="#Have-fun-with-Git" class="headerlink" title="Have fun with Git"></a>Have fun with Git</h3><h4 id="1-Create-a-local-git-repository"><a href="#1-Create-a-local-git-repository" class="headerlink" title="1 Create a local git repository"></a>1 Create a local git repository</h4><p>第一件是你需要做的就是在一个文件夹中创建一个git repository。<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">git init<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>切记，那文件夹最好的空的文件夹。</p><p>之后你可以用这个命令来查看你是否成功创建了一个git repository。<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">git status<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>请记住这命令，因为在后面你可能常需要用到它。 这命令的功能也简单就是查看当前git 的状态。如果你输入这个命令的话你会看到<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">On branch master <span class="hljs-comment">#你当前的位置</span><br><br>No commits yet <span class="hljs-comment">#你是否commit</span><br><br>nothing to commit (create/copy files and use <span class="hljs-string">&quot;git add&quot;</span> to track)<br><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>之后我会逐步讲解什么是<code>branch</code>， <code>add</code> 还是 <code>commit</code>。</p><p>Note: 在你建立一个git repository它会在你的文件夹中生成一个<code>.git</code>的文件夹。这文件夹一般是隐形的。在Linux你可以按<code>ctrl+h</code>来显示它。</p><h4 id="2-Create-a-new-file-to-the-repo"><a href="#2-Create-a-new-file-to-the-repo" class="headerlink" title="2 Create a new file to the repo"></a>2 Create a new file to the repo</h4><p>在Git文档中可以你可以手动创建一个文件或者也可以<br><figure class="highlight cmake"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs cmake">touch <span class="hljs-keyword">test</span>.txt<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>其实这里并没有任何特别的或者需要主要的地方。现在我们可以尝试用<code>git status</code>看看会发生什么。</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">On branch master<br><br>No commits yet<br><br>Untracked files:<br>  (use <span class="hljs-string">&quot;git add &lt;file&gt;...&quot;</span> to include <span class="hljs-keyword">in</span> what will be committed)<br>test.text<br><br>nothing added to commit but untracked files present (use <span class="hljs-string">&quot;git add&quot;</span> to track)<br><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>你看到在<code>untracked files</code>多出了一个<code>test.text</code>。这就是git的精髓，同时也涉及到的<code>add</code> 和<code>commit</code> 的功能。下一章见。</p><h4 id="3-Add-and-commit"><a href="#3-Add-and-commit" class="headerlink" title="3 Add and commit"></a>3 <em>Add</em> and <em>commit</em></h4><h4 id="4-the-twig-branch"><a href="#4-the-twig-branch" class="headerlink" title="4 the twig branch"></a>4 the twig <em>branch</em></h4><p>如果你懂的如何巧妙的利用branch，这会让你的工作效率大大提高。你可以想象git repository就像一棵大树。开始的draft branch就是树根，之后一个完整的树会有很多树根。branch的好处在于它可以保存不同的version，以及方便查询之前的version。也就是说你可以在不同的树枝之前来回切换</p><p>创建一个branch也很简单，只需要<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">git branch &lt;branch name&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>每次你创建一个branch也就相当于你拷贝你目前的branch。</p><p>之后切换到不同的branch就可以用<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">git checkeout &lt;branch name&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><h4 id="5-Overwrtting-with-merge"><a href="#5-Overwrtting-with-merge" class="headerlink" title="5 Overwrtting with merge"></a>5 Overwrtting with <em>merge</em></h4><h4 id="5-Advanced-of-Git-can-be-skipped"><a href="#5-Advanced-of-Git-can-be-skipped" class="headerlink" title="5 Advanced of Git (can be skipped)"></a>5 Advanced of Git (can be skipped)</h4><h2 id="GitHub"><a href="#GitHub" class="headerlink" title="GitHub"></a>GitHub</h2><h3 id="What-is-the-difference-between-GitHub-and-Git"><a href="#What-is-the-difference-between-GitHub-and-Git" class="headerlink" title="What is the difference between GitHub and Git"></a>What is the difference between GitHub and Git</h3><blockquote><p>Git is the bow, your code is the arrow, and Github is the target.</p></blockquote><p>Simply, git is a software, it is also a local “warehouse” at your pc where you can save different versions of the code and documents. GitHub is an online “warehouse”, where you can also save your code and its version.</p><h3 id="Create-an-account"><a href="#Create-an-account" class="headerlink" title="Create an account"></a>Create an account</h3><p>I won’t introduce it in detail here, see GitHub official website</p><h3 id="Create-a-repository-at-GitHub"><a href="#Create-a-repository-at-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Create a repository at GitHub"></a>Create a repository at GitHub</h3><blockquote><p>Keep in mind that rules about cheating and plagiarism may make it necessary to use private repositories for group work!</p></blockquote><h3 id="Work-with-Git"><a href="#Work-with-Git" class="headerlink" title="Work with Git"></a>Work with Git</h3><p>当你创建好了一个repository at GitHub。那么你就可以把你当地的文件保存到GitHub的repository。<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">git remote add origin &lt;server&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><h2 id="Common-commands"><a href="#Common-commands" class="headerlink" title="Common commands"></a>Common commands</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">git init <span class="hljs-comment"># Create a new local repository</span><br>git status <span class="hljs-comment"># List the files you&#x27;ve changed and those you still need to add or commit</span><br>git remote add origin &lt;server&gt; <span class="hljs-comment"># Connect to a remote repository</span><br>git push origin &lt;branchname&gt; <span class="hljs-comment"># Push the branch to your remote repository</span><br>git pull <span class="hljs-comment"># Fetch and merge changes on the remote server to your working directory</span><br>git merge &lt;branchname&gt; <span class="hljs-comment"># To merge a different branch into your active branch</span><br><br>git add &lt;filename&gt; <span class="hljs-comment"># Add one or more files to staging (index)</span><br>git commit -m <span class="hljs-string">&quot;Commit message&quot;</span> <span class="hljs-comment"># Commit changes to head (but not yet to the remote repository)</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>For more and detalj information pleace click <a class="btn" href="https://confluence.atlassian.com/bitbucketserver/basic-git-commands-776639767.html"  title="title" target="_blank">--> here <--</a></p><h2 id="Edit-LaTeX-together"><a href="#Edit-LaTeX-together" class="headerlink" title="Edit $\LaTeX$ together"></a>Edit $\LaTeX$ together</h2><p>Now you are ready !</p><ol><li>创建一个git文件夹，并包含texfil</li><li>发送到GitHub</li><li>通知你的队友以及把GitHub的网站分享给他们</li><li>队友们pull</li></ol><h2 id="最后说几句"><a href="#最后说几句" class="headerlink" title="最后说几句"></a>最后说几句</h2><p>其实Git强大在于它并不限制与tex 文档，</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Camputer</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Git</tag>
      
      <tag>LaTeX</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Endimentionell analys</title>
    <link href="/endimentionell-analys.html"/>
    <url>/endimentionell-analys.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Instuderingsfrågor för Endimensionell analys</strong></p><h2 id="B1"><a href="#B1" class="headerlink" title="B1"></a>B1</h2><h3 id="Kapitel-1"><a href="#Kapitel-1" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 1"></a>Kapitel 1</h3><p><strong>1. Vilka talmängder betecknas med N, Z, Q och R?</strong></p><p>N = naturliga talen; 1,2,3,4,5<br>Z = alla heltal; ..-2,-1,0,1,2..<br>Q = Rationella tal;  a/b där a och b ∈ Z != 0.<br>R = Reella tal; alla tal som finns i tallinjen.</p><p><strong>2. Vad betyder tecknen ∈, ⊆, ∅, ⇒ respektive ⇔?</strong></p><p>∈ = tillhör, ex om vi har en mängd M = {2,32,1} då 2 ∈ M, dvs element 2 tillhör mängden M.<br>⊆ = delmängd, ex, {2,34} är en delmängd av {2,5,3,23,34}<br>∅ = tomma mängden, dvs den mängden inte består några elementer.<br>$\Rightarrow$ = implikation, påstående leder bara till ena hållet men inte det andra. Ex. R $\Leftarrow$ N, men det medför inte om A $!\Rightarrow$ B<br>⇔ = ekvivalens, om vi har två påstående A och B. Om A och B ska vara ekvivalens så myclet de implicerar varandra. Dvs om B är sant så är A sant och om A är sant så är B också sant.</p><p><strong>3. Varför kan symbolerna ⇒ och ⇔ inte användas mellan två uttryck?</strong></p><p>Ett matematiskt uttryck ger ingen påstående därför kan man inte påvisa om det är sant eller icke sant!</p><h3 id="Kapitel-2"><a href="#Kapitel-2" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 2"></a>Kapitel 2</h3><p><strong>4. Hur adderas, multipliceras och divideras bråk?</strong></p><p>Skoja du?</p><p><strong>5. Vad menas med kvadratkomplettering? Kan alla andragradspolynom, t.ex. även $x^2$, kvadratkompletteras?</strong></p><p>kvadratkomplettering är ett omskrvingsssätt för andragradspolynom. Alla andragradspolynom går att kvadratkompletteras, tyvärr har jag inte bevis för det. $x^2 = (x+0)^2+0$ :)</p><p><strong>6. Skriv upp formeln för polynomdivision, $f(x)\over g(x)$= . . ., och använd denna för att bevisa faktorsatsen.</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-P"><a href="#Kapitel-P" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel P"></a>Kapitel P</h3><p>Jag återkommer med den!<br><strong>7. Vad är det för skillnad mellan ett axiom, en definition och en sats?</strong><br><strong>8. Vad menas med parallella linjer i planet?</strong><br><strong>9. Visa att vertikalvinklar är lika stora.</strong><br><strong>10. Formulera ett axiom som handlar om linjer och vinklar.</strong><br><strong>11. Vad menas med kongruenta trianglar? Formulera kongruensaxiomen.</strong><br><strong>12. Vad är vinkelsumman i en triangel respektive fyrhörning? Ge bevis.</strong><br><strong>13. Formulera och bevisa yttervinkelsatsen.</strong><br><strong>14. Definiera följande: cirkel, parallellogram, romb, parallelltrapets, rektangel och kvadrat.</strong><br><strong>15. Visa att varje rektangel är en parallellogram och att varje romb är en parallellogram.</strong><br><strong>16. Formulera och bevisa parallellogramsatsen.</strong><br><strong>17. Visa att diagonalerna i en parallellogram delar varandra mitt itu.</strong><br><strong>18. Formulera och bevisa satsen om en likbent triangel samt basvinkelsatsen.</strong><br><strong>19. Vad menas med en sluten polygon och hur kan man beräkna arean av området innanför en sådan?</strong><br><strong>20. Bevisa formler för triangelns, parallellogrammens samt parallelltrapetsets area.</strong><br><strong>21. Formulera och bevisa Pythagoras sats.</strong><br><strong>22. Om hypotenusan och en katet i en rätvinklig triangel är lika med motsvarande sidor i en annan, hur kan man då dra slutsatsen att de två trianglarna är kongruenta?</strong><br><strong>23. Formulera och bevisa omvändningen till Pythagoras sats. (Det finns ytterligare ett bevis bland övningarna. Välj själv det du tycker är enklast.)</strong><br><strong>24. Formulera transversalsatsen.</strong><br><strong>25. Vad menas med att två trianglar är likformiga?</strong><br><strong>26. Formulera topptriangelsatsen.</strong><br><strong>27. Formulera bisektrissatsen.</strong><br><strong>28. Formulera alla likformighetsfallen.</strong><br><strong>29. Formulera och bevisa randvinkelsatsen samt två omedelbara följder av denna.</strong><br><strong>30. Definiera en tangent till en cirkel och ange en viktig egenskap hos denna.</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-3"><a href="#Kapitel-3" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 3"></a>Kapitel 3</h3><p><strong>31. Vad är skillnaden mellan en ekvation och ett uttryck? Ge exempel.</strong></p><p>En ekvation innehåller en likhettecken och obetankta. Ex $x^2=x-2$. Medan ett uttryck innehåller inte en likhetstecken däremot kan de har en eller flera obetankta variabler. Ex $x+2$</p><p><strong>32. Vad menas med att två ekvationer är ekvivalenta?</strong></p><p>Ex. $(x+1)^2$ är ju ekvivalenta med ek. $x^2 + 2x +1$</p><p><strong>33. Vad kan man göra med en ekvation, om man vill få en ny ekvivalent ekvation? Ge tre exempel på operationer där en ny ekvation uppstår, som inte säkert är ekvivalent med den ursprungliga.</strong></p><p>kvadratkomplettering ger då ekvivalent med den ursprungliga ekvationen. De tre operationerna som inte ger ekvivalens med den ursprungliga ekvationen är nämligen 1) kvadrera båda led, 2) multipliceras båda led med term, där den ena led är noll, 3)dra kvadratoten ur båda led, eller likande. Kan du visa och argumentera varför?</p><p><strong>34. Härled lösningsformeln för andragradsekvationen $x^2 + px + q = 0$.</strong></p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">x^2+px+q=0 \\ \Leftrightarrow \\(x+  {p\over2})^2-({p\over2})^2+q=0 \\ \Leftrightarrow ({})</script><p>Jag orkar inte mer, ser s.36 för fullständigt bevis.</p><p><strong>35. Hur angriper du olikheter som innehåller polynom och kvoter av polynom?</strong></p><p>Det bästa sättet är att samlas alla termer i ena led. Försök att faktorisera täljaren så långt det gå. Notera nollställer i täljaren och nämnaren. Notera även att nollställer i nämnaren är ej definerad. Sedan studeras teckentabellet och dra fram slutsatsen.</p><h3 id="Kapitel-4"><a href="#Kapitel-4" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 4"></a>Kapitel 4</h3><p><strong>36. Vad karakteriserar en aritmetisk summa? Hur beräknar man en sådan?</strong><br><strong>37. Skriv upp och härled formeln för en geometrisk summa.</strong><br><strong>38. Definiera n! samt $\binom{n}{k}$. Vad är $\binom{n}{0}$ och $\binom{n}{1}$?</strong><br><strong>39. Skriv $(a + b)^5$ som en summa. Skriv upp den allmänna binomialsatsen.</strong><br><strong>40. Skriv upp Pascals triangel till och med n = 6</strong><br><strong>41. Vad karakteriserar en geometrisk talföljd?</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-A-och-5"><a href="#Kapitel-A-och-5" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel A och 5"></a>Kapitel A och 5</h3><p><strong>42. Definiera begreppet riktningskoefficient för en linje i planet. Vilka värden kan den anta?</strong><br><strong>43. Hur får man fram en ekvation för en rät linje a) om man känner riktningskoefficienten och en punkt på linjen; b) om man känner två punkter på linjen?</strong><br><strong>44. Hur får man fram ekvationen för normalen till en linje i en given punkt på linjen?</strong><br><strong>45. Ange en ekvation för en parabel med symmetrilinje parallell med x-axeln och vertex i $(x_0, y_0)$, som ligger a) till höger och b) till vänster om linjen x = x0 i xy-planet.</strong><br><strong>46. Definiera vad som menas med ”absolutbeloppet av ett reellt tal”.</strong><br><strong>47. Skriv upp formler för avståndet mellan två punkter dels på tallinjen, dels i planet.</strong><br><strong>48. Härled cirkelns ekvation.</strong><br><strong>49. Skriv upp en ekvation för en ellips med halvaxlarna a och b och medelpunkten $(x_0, y_0)$ samt rita en figur.</strong><br><strong>50. Ange en ekvation för en hyperbel samt ange dess asymptoter. Rita hyperbeln och asymptoterna i en figur och sätt ut skärningarna med koordinataxlarna. Vad händer om x och y byter plats i ekvationen?</strong><br><strong>51. Ange asymptoterna till hyperbeln $\frac{x^2}{a^2}-\frac{y^2}{b^2}=1$</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-7"><a href="#Kapitel-7" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 7"></a>Kapitel 7</h3><p><strong>52. Beskriv vad som menas med en funktion samt funktionens definitionsmängd och värdemängd.</strong></p><p>En funktion menar man att det är en regel som till varje reellt tal som ordnar precis ett annat tal som är också reellt. $f:\R \rightarrow \R$(Så klart funktionen är inte begränsad inom reellt analys, det kan också vara linjära funktion,viktorvärd och komplexvärd funktion). En funktion består av definitionsmängd vilket är då en delmängd av $\R$ samt en värdemängd som är en bild av definitionsmängd.</p><p><strong>53. Låt $f$ vara en funktion vars definitionsmängd och värdemängd är delmängder av R. Vad menas med grafen av $f$?</strong></p><p>$G_f = { x,f(x); x\in D_f }$ med ord så menar man att graften till en funktion är då den delmängd av planet som ges av alla sådana punkter dvs $G_f$</p><p><strong>54. Vad menas med inversen $f^{-1}$ till en funktion $f$? Har alla funktioner en invers? Ange ett tillräckligt villkor för att det ska finnas en invers.</strong></p><p>Om en funktion är en injektiv funktion så är funktionen inversbara. Det vill säga $x_1 \ne x_2 \Rightarrow f(x_1)\ne f(x_2)$, för alla $x_1,x_2 \in D_f$. Detta innebär även att alla jämna funktioner är därför ej injectiv därmed ej inversebar om vi inte tillägga restriktionen till den. Därför ex. $f(x) = x^2$ och ex $f(x)= \sin(x)$ har ej invers.</p><p><strong>55. Definiera begreppen växande och strängt växande funktion.</strong></p><p>Om en funktion är växande så gäller det</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">x_1 < x_2 \Rightarrow f(x_1) \leqslant f(x_2)</script><p>Om det är avtagande så gäller det</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">x_1 < x_2 \Rightarrow f(x_1) \geqslant f(x_2)</script><p>för alla $x_1,x_2 \in D_f$.<br>En monoton är då en funktion som är växande eller avtagande.</p><p><strong>56. Ge exempel på en funktion i intervallet $1 ≤ x &lt; \infty$ som är både strängt växande och uppåt begränsad.</strong></p><p>Det finns två typer av begränsad funktion nämnligen uppåt och nedåt begränsad.<br>Vi säger at en funktion är uppåt begränsad om det existerar ett tal $M $ sådana att</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">f(x) \leqslant M</script><p>för alla $x\in D_f$<br>Det motsvarande resonomang för nedåt begränsad funktion.</p><p>Exemple på begränsad funktioner $f(x) = \arctan(x), f(x)= \frac{1}{x}$</p><p><strong>57. Definiera begreppen jämn respektive udda funktion.</strong></p><p>En jämn funktion innebär $f(-x)= f(x)$ medan en undda funktion så är $f(-x) = -f(x)$.</p><p><strong>58. Ge tre exempel på jämna funktioner och tre exempel på udda funktioner.</strong></p><p>Jämn funktion, ex $f(x)=x^2, f(x)=x^2+1$ eller $f(x)=x^4+x^2$. Udda funktion, ex $f(x)=x, f(x)=x^3-1$ eller $f(x)=x^7+x^3+x+1$.</p><h3 id="Kapitel-8-1–8-3"><a href="#Kapitel-8-1–8-3" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 8.1–8.3"></a>Kapitel 8.1–8.3</h3><p><strong>59. Rita graferna till $f(x)=e^{\alpha x}$ och $f(x)=x^{\alpha}$ för några olika $\alpha$. Rita graferna till $f(x)=ln(x)$ och $f(x)=ln|x|$.</strong></p><p>Ok…Sök google om du inte kan det i huvud.</p><p><strong>60. Bevisa logaritmlagarna med utgångspunkt från potenslagarna.</strong><br><strong>61….</strong><br><strong>62. Uttryck $^a\log x$ med hjälp av $\ln x$.</strong><br>Ok.</p><h3 id="Kapitel-T-och-8-4"><a href="#Kapitel-T-och-8-4" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel T och 8.4"></a>Kapitel T och 8.4</h3><p><strong>63. Definiera de trigonometriska funktionerna, dels i specialfallet av en rätvinklig triangel, dels generellt via enhetscirkeln.</strong><br><strong>64. Visa trigonometriska ettan.</strong><br><strong>65. Använd enhetscirkeln och kongruenta trianglar för att visa formler för $\sin(−α)$, $\sin(90−α)$, $\sin(180◦ − α)$ samt motsvarande formler för cosinus.</strong><br><strong>66. Formulera och bevisa areasatsen.</strong><br><strong>67. Formulera och bevisa sinussatsen.</strong><br><strong>68. Formulera och bevisa cosinussatsen.</strong><br><strong>69. Hur definieras vinkelmåttet radian?</strong><br><strong>70. Rita graferna till funktionerna sin x, cos x, tan x och cot x.</strong><br><strong>**71. Illustrera dubbelolikheten sin x &lt; x &lt; tan x då 0 &lt; x &lt; $\frac{\pi}{2}$</strong><br><strong>72. Skriv upp de trigonometriska additionsformlerna. Ange formler för dubbla vinkeln för sinus respektive cosinus. Ge bevis.</strong><br><strong>73. Redogör för hjälpvinkelmetoden vid behandling av uttryck av formen a sin ωx + b cos ωx.</strong><br><strong>74. Givet radien i en cirkel, skriv upp formler för dess omkrets respektive area.</strong><br><strong>75. Ange sambandet mellan båglängd, vinkel och radie för en cirkelsektor, dels då vinkeln mäts i grader, dels i radianer.</strong><br><strong>76. Givet radien och båglängden för en cirkelsektor, ange dess area.</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-8-5"><a href="#Kapitel-8-5" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 8.5"></a>Kapitel 8.5</h3><p><strong>77. Definiera funktionerna arcsin x, arccos x och arctan x. Ange deras definitions- och värdemängder.</strong></p><p>Dessa funktioner är invers till trigonometriska funktion. Eftersom de trigonometriska funktionerna är inte injectiva därför måste vi sätta restriktionen på det inversa trigonometriska funktioner. Restriktionen kan välja godtycklig, detta visar sig att det finns en stor fördel inom komplex analys.</p><p>$\arccos$ och $\arcsin$ har då $D_f = [-1,1]$, medan värdemängderna är $[0, \pi]$ respektive $[-\frac{\pi}{2},\frac{\pi}{2}]$</p><p>$\arctan$ har då $D_f = x\in \R$ och $V_f = ]-\frac{\pi}{2},\frac{\pi}{2}[$</p><p><strong>78. Rita graferna till funktionerna arcsin x, arccos x och arctan x</strong></p><p>Gör det själv i Geogebra …om du inte kan det i huvud</p><h3 id="Kapitel-9"><a href="#Kapitel-9" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 9"></a>Kapitel 9</h3><p><strong>79. Låt α &gt; 0 och a &gt; 1. Arrangera funktionerna $x^α$, $\ln x$ och $a^x$ i storleksordning för stora värden på $x$. Precisera svaret i form av gränsvärden då x → $\infty$.</strong><br><strong>80. Definiera talet $e$.</strong><br><strong>81. Definiera innebörden av uttrycket ”funktionen $f$ är kontinuerlig i punkten $a$”.</strong><br><strong>82. Ange några egenskaper hos kontinuerliga funktioner på slutna, begränsade intervall.</strong><br><strong>83. Lär dig standardgränsvärdena nummer (9.19) till (9.25) i läroboken. Utgående från de två gränsvärdena $(1+\frac{1}{x})^x \rightarrow \pm \infty $ då $x \rightarrow \pm \infty$, och $\frac{a^x}{x^a} \rightarrow \infty$ då $x \rightarrow \infty$.lär dig härleda (9.20), (9.23), (9.24) och (9.25).</strong><br><strong>84. Uttryck av formen ${f(x)}^{g(x)}$ kan skrivas om med hjälp av funktionerna exp och ln. Hur då?</strong><br><strong>85. Vad meanas med att “serien $\sum_{k=1}^{\infty}u^k$” är konvergent?</strong><br><strong>86. Låt $\sum_{k=1}^{\infty}u^k$vara en konvergent serie. Vad meanas med seriens summan?</strong><br><strong>87. Visa att den geometrisa serien $\sum_{k=0}^{\infty}u^k$ konvergent precis då $|x|&lt;1$ och ange dess summa.</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-10"><a href="#Kapitel-10" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 10"></a>Kapitel 10</h3><p><strong>88. Formulera definitionen av att funktionen $f$ är deriverbar i punkten $a$.</strong></p><p>Om vi antas att $f$ är definerad i en omgivning av punkten $a$. Vi säger då att f är deriverbar i $a$ om $ \lim_{h\rightarrow 0}\frac{f(a+h)-f(a)}{h}$. Det vill säga om gränsvärdet existerar i omgivning av punkten $a$, och den gränsvärdet kalls derivatan av $f$ i punktne $a$.</p><p><strong>89. Definiera beteckningen $f^{‘}(a)$.</strong></p><p>Det före kommer flera olika beteckningar för derivattan. Här är några exempl, $Df, y’, \frac{dy}{dx}, \frac{d}{dx}f…$</p><p><strong>90. Visa att om $f$ är deriverbar i $a$ så är $f$ kontinuerlig i $a$. Ge exempel på att omvändningen inte gäller.</strong></p><p>En rikigt bra exemple på det är Weierstrass function.</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">f(x)= \sum_{n=0}^{\infty}a^n \cos(b^n \pi x)</script><p>Där $ab = a + \frac{3}{2} \pi $<br>Den funktion är kontinuerlig i hela intervall men inte deriverbar i en enda punkt. Om  du är sucken på det så BEVISA den!!!</p><p><strong>91. Rita en funktion som i $x = 0$ är a) diskontinuerlig, b) kontinuerlig men ej deriverbar, c) deriverbar.</strong><br><strong>92. Härled derivatan av $e^x$ genom att utgå från derivatans definition.</strong><br><strong>93. Ange några fysikaliska tolkningar av uttrycket $f^{‘}(t_0)$, där f är t.ex. en sträcka, temperatur eller volym.</strong><br><strong>94. Vad menas med tangenten till en funktionskurva $y = f(x)$ i en punkt $(a, f(a))$ på grafen? Svara såväl med ord som i form av en ekvation.</strong><br><strong>95. Hur får man fram en ekvation för normalen till en kurva i en given punkt på kurvan?</strong><br><strong>96. Ange formler för derivatan av a) $f(g(x))$, b) $f^{-1}(x)$  c) $f(x)g(x)$, d) $\frac{f(x)}{g(x)}$. Bevisa c) och d).</strong></p><p>$f(g(x))’(x) = f’(g(x))\cdot g(x)$<br>$f^{-1}(x)= \frac{1}{f’(x)}$<br>$(f\cdot g)’(x) = f’(x)g(x)+f(x)g’(x)$<br>$({f\over g})’(x) = \frac{f’(x)g(x)-f(x)g’(x)}{g(x)^2}$</p><p>Beviset härvisa jag till boken, ser s.214</p><p><strong>97. Härled derivatan av ln $x$, $x$ &gt; 0, genom att utgå från derivatan av $e^x$. Härled sedan derivatan av $\ln |x|$, $x \ne 0$.</strong><br><strong>98. Skriv upp derivatorna av alla standardfunktionerna; se (10.9)–(10.20) i läroboken.</strong><br><strong>99. Härled derivatan av $\sin x$ genom att utgå från derivatans definition. (Gränsvärdet $\lim_{h \rightarrow 0} \frac{cos h−1}{h} = 0$ får användas.)</strong><br><strong>100. Härled derivatorna av arcsin x och arctan x.</strong><br><strong>101. Definiera innebörden av uttrycket “$f$ har lokalt minimum i punkten a”.</strong><br><strong>102. Vad menas med en lokal extrempunkt respektive en stationär punkt till en funktion?</strong><br><strong>103. Hur hittar man eventuella lokala extrempunkter till en deriverbar funktion?</strong><br><strong>104. Formulera medelvärdessatsen och förklara dess innehåll med en figur.</strong><br><strong>105. Bevisa, med hjälp av medelvärdessatsen, att om en funktion definierad på ett intervall har en derivata som är positiv så är funktionen strängt växande.</strong><br><strong>106. Bevisa, med hjälp av medelvärdessatsen, att om en funktion definierad på ett intervall har en derivata som är noll så är funktionen konstant.</strong><br><strong>107. Vad menas med att en rät linje $y = ax + b$ är en (sned) asymptot till en funktionskurva $y = f(x)$, då $x \rightarrow \infty$?</strong><br><strong>108. Hur bestämmer man eventuella asymptoter till en rationell funktion?</strong><br><strong>109. Hur löser man ett optimeringsproblem för en deriverbar funktion f(x), x ∈ I, där I är ett intervall? Ange ett villkor som garanterar att ett största och ett minsta värde finns.</strong><br><strong>110. Ange en metod för att visa en olikhet av formen $f(x)$ &gt; $g(x)$, x ∈ I, där I är ett intervall ($f$ och $g$ är deriverbara).</strong></p><h2 id="B2"><a href="#B2" class="headerlink" title="B2"></a>B2</h2><h3 id="Kapitel-11"><a href="#Kapitel-11" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 11"></a>Kapitel 11</h3><p><strong>19. Skriv upp Maclaurins formel med Lagranges restterm.</strong><br><strong>20. För vilka x är Maclaurinpolynomet pn(x) en god approximation av $f(x)$ ? Varför vill man approximera med polynom?</strong><br><strong>21. Hur avgör man hur noggrann approximationen i föregående fråga är?</strong><br><strong>22. Skriv upp Taylors formel (utveckling kring $x = a$) med Lagranges restterm.</strong><br><strong>23. Skriv upp standardutvecklingarna (11.5)–(11.10) i läroboken.</strong><br>**24. Visa med Maclaurinutveckling att $e^x = \sum_{k=0}^{\infty} \frac{x^k}{k!}$ for varje $x \in \R$.</p><p>(Använd gränsvärdet $\lim_{n\rightarrow\infty}\frac{a^n}{n!}=0$)**</p><h3 id="Kapitel-12"><a href="#Kapitel-12" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 12"></a>Kapitel 12</h3><p><strong>25. Vad menas med uttrycket ”$F$ är en primitiv funktion till $f$ i intervallet $I$”?</strong></p><p>En funktion $F$ kallas en primitiv funktion till $f$ på intervallet $I$ om $F’(x) = f(x)$ för att $x\in I$.</p><p><strong>26. Bevisa att om $F$ och $G$ är primitiver till samma funktion $f$, så är $G(x) = F(x) + C$, där $C$ är en konstant.</strong></p><p>Om $G(x)$ och $F(x) + C$  primitiver till samma funktion, då om vi derivera $G(x)$ och $F(x) + C$ då försvinner konstanten $C$.</p><p><strong>27. Lär dig de ”elementära primitiva funktionerna” på sid. 281 i boken.</strong></p><p>Ok</p><p><strong>28. Skriv upp och bevisa formeln för partialintegration. Ange även ett exempel där det är lämpligt att använda partialintegration.</strong></p><p>Man använder partialintegration om det är produkt mellan två termer. Ex. $e^xx^2$, partialintegration går också bra att bestämma primitiv till $1 \cdot \ln x$.</p><p>Bevis:</p><p><strong>29. Hur utför man variabelbyte när man bestämmer en primitiv funktion? Vilken deriveringsregel ligger bakom?</strong></p><p><strong>30. Beskriv ansatsprinciperna vid partialbråksuppdelning samt hur man bestämmer ansatskoefficienterna.</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-13"><a href="#Kapitel-13" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 13"></a>Kapitel 13</h3><p><strong>31. Vad är en Riemannsumma till en kontinuerlig funktion $f$ i intervallet $[a, b]$? Förklara ingående beteckningar med hjälp av en figur. Vad händer då indelningen förfinas?</strong></p><p><strong>32. Lär dig räknelagarna för integraler (13.8)–(13.11) i läroboken.</strong></p><p>ok</p><p><strong>33. Formulera triangelolikheten för integraler. Troliggör med en skiss.</strong></p><p><strong>34. Formulera integralkalkylens medelvärdessats och förklara den med hjälp av en figur.</strong></p><p><strong>35. Formulera och bevisa analysens huvudsats med hjälp av integralkalkylens medelvärdessats.</strong></p><p><strong>36. Låt $f$ vara kontinuerlig i $a ≤ x ≤ b$. Använd huvudsatsen för att bevisa insättningsformeln <script type="math/tex">\int_{a}^bf(x)dx=F(b)-F(a)</script>, där $F$ är en (godtycklig) primitiv till $f$.</strong></p><p><strong>37. Vad menas med uttrycket ”den generaliserade integralen$ \int_a^{\infty}f(x) dx$ är konvergent”?</strong></p><p><strong>38. På vilka sätt kan integraler vara generaliserade? Hur beräknar man dem (om de är konvergenta)?</strong></p><p><strong>39. För vilka $a$ är de generaliserade integralerna $\int_1^{\infty}\frac{1}{x^a}dx, \int_0^{1}\frac{1}{x^a}dx, \int_0^{\infty}\frac{1}{x^a}dx$ konvergenta?</strong></p><p><strong>40. Hur lyder jämförelsesatsen för generaliserade integraler av formen $\int_a^{\infty}f(x)dx$? Illustrera med en figur.</strong></p><p><strong>41. Hur kan $\sum_{k=1}^n f(k)$uppskattas med en integral av $f$, om $f$ är en avtagande (växande) funktion. Rita figur.</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-14"><a href="#Kapitel-14" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 14"></a>Kapitel 14</h3><p><strong>42. Hur beräknar man arean av området mellan två funktionskurvor?</strong><br><strong>43. Förklara den så kallade skivformeln $\int_a^b A(x)dx$ för volymen av en kropp.</strong><br><strong>44. Då grafen $y = f(x), a ≤ x ≤ b$, roterar kring x-axeln uppstår en rotationsyta, som tillsamans med avgränsningar vid $x = a$ och $x = b$ bildar en rotationskropp. Förklara hur man kan få fram formler för rotationsytans area samt rotationskroppens volym.</strong><br><strong>45. Kontrollera att du i tyngdpunktsberäkningar förstår hur symboliska integraler som $\int_K x dm$ ska översättas till vanliga integraler. Vad betyder $x$ och $dm$?</strong><br><strong>46. Ange formeln för längden av en kurva i planet som ges på parameterform. Hur ser formeln ut i specialfallet då kurvan är grafen till en funktion $f$?</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-15"><a href="#Kapitel-15" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 15"></a>Kapitel 15</h3><p><strong>47. Vad menas med en lösning till en differentialekvation? Visa att $y=e^{x^2}$ är en lösning till $y’’+2xy’-2y=0$.</strong><br><strong>48. . Hur löser man en differentialekvation av formen a) $y’+g(x)y = h(x)$? b) $g(y)y’ = h(x)$?</strong><br><strong>49.  Visa att den allmänna lösningen till differentialekvationen $y’ = ay$ är $y = Ce^{ax}$</strong><br><strong>50. Hur löser du integralekvationen $y(x) = A +\int_0^x f(t)y(t) dt$, där A är en konstant?</strong><br><strong>51. Vad betyder $y_h$ respektive $y_p$ i framställningen $y = y_h+y_p$ av lösningarna till en differentialekvation av formen $y’’ + a(x)y’ + b(x)y = g(x)$.</strong><br><strong>52.  Ange $y_h$ i föregående uppgift om $a$ och $b$ är konstanter. Vilka olika fall måste särskiljas?</strong><br><strong>53. Ange alla $y_h$ i föregående uppgift på reell form om $a$ och $b$ är reella konstanter.</strong><br><strong>54. Hur hittar du yp när $g(x)$ är av formen<br>a) konstant,<br>b) polynom,<br>c) polynom · $e^{αx}$,<br>d) polynom · $\cos βx$ (alternativt $\sin βx$),<br>e) en summa av funktioner av ovanstående form?</strong><br><strong>55. Ange den allmänna lösningen till differentialekvationen $y’’ + ω ^2y = 0$. Ge en fysikalisk tolkning av resultatet.</strong><br><strong>56.  Vad menas med resonans och när kan resonans uppträda?</strong></p><p>dede</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Mathematics</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>From zero to 1, how to create your own blog</title>
    <link href="/from-zero-to-1-how-to-create-your-own-blog.html"/>
    <url>/from-zero-to-1-how-to-create-your-own-blog.html</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/blog2.jpg" alt=""></p><h2 id="Background"><a href="#Background" class="headerlink" title="Background"></a>Background</h2><h3 id="Why-I-want-strart-writing-blog"><a href="#Why-I-want-strart-writing-blog" class="headerlink" title="Why I want strart writing blog"></a>Why I want strart writing blog</h3><p>Creating a blog was an idea I had in few weeks ago. I tried many times before and after but all ended in failure. Recently, my idea of creating a blog has become stronger and stronger. Accidently I found out that I can create my own blog by using GitHub. And there is what you see now.</p><p>Before I was a person who relied heavily on social media. Every time I turn on the phone, the first thing I do is watch video,  post and check what others have done aimlessly. At that moment I don’t feel my-self. In this era of “information explosion”, I found slowly that I became unable to think independently. So I gradually stay away from various social media such as Facebook, WeChat, QQ, etc. The main reason why I stay away from them is very simple because they give me innutritious information all the time.</p><p>I hope that in this blog I can quietly be my-self and write down my true feelings. Here I hope I can think freely, without considering other people’s feelings. This is also my original intention of creating this blog. In addition, I also want to record every moment of this young man, after all you are still worth remembering in this rushed world. Whenever this young man wants to look back, at least there are stories that belong to him, and some of his whimsical thoughts.</p><p>  2020-12-14</p><p>  Z.H.</p><h2 id="How-to-create-a-blog-using-GitHub-and-Hexo"><a href="#How-to-create-a-blog-using-GitHub-and-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="How to create a blog using GitHub and Hexo"></a>How to create a blog using GitHub and Hexo</h2><p>In this page I gonna introduce how to use Github and Hexo to build your own static website or blog. Attention, all the install here is based on operatingsystem Linux disto <code>Ubuntu 20.04.1</code>. Let’s go it will be fun and fun :D.</p><h2 id="GitHub"><a href="#GitHub" class="headerlink" title="GitHub"></a>GitHub</h2><h3 id="Short-intro-about-GitHub-and-why-GitHub"><a href="#Short-intro-about-GitHub-and-why-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Short intro about GitHub and why GitHub"></a>Short intro about GitHub and why GitHub</h3><p>If you never use GitHub before then to <a href="https://github.com/">https://github.com/</a> and create an account. There are some avantage to build a blog.</p><ul><li>It is totally free and convenient.</li><li>Due the static file, it has fast access speed.</li><li>GitHub has versioncontrol functionality. Hence your data of each version of your blog is safe and you can restore it if you want.</li><li>You can do and design whatever you want.</li></ul><h3 id="Create-a-repository-at-GitHub"><a href="#Create-a-repository-at-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Create a repository at GitHub"></a>Create a repository at GitHub</h3><p>Loggin at GitHub and click <code>New repository</code>. Here you must pay attention that your name of repository must be <code>&#39;your username&#39;.github.io</code>. Otherwises it would not work. I mean it still work..but not enough elegant.</p><h2 id="Hexo"><a href="#Hexo" class="headerlink" title="Hexo"></a>Hexo</h2><h3 id="What-is-Hexo-and-why-you-need-it"><a href="#What-is-Hexo-and-why-you-need-it" class="headerlink" title="What is Hexo and why you need it?"></a>What is Hexo and why you need it?</h3><p>Basically Hexo is a blog framework that allows you to quickly build a blog. In my case I chose Hexo because it is fast, concise and efficient. Hexo is written by Node.js and it also supports Markdown and many other packages. Hence you actually don’t need that much programming och computer knowledge like HTML、css、JavaScript etc. The only thing you should learn or feel familiar with is Markdown. Of course if you want your blog to look prefekt and beautiful that is strong recommend that you master the basics programming language like HTML.</p><h3 id="Install-Hexo"><a href="#Install-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="Install Hexo"></a>Install Hexo</h3><p>This installation is based on operating system Linux distro Ubuntu. The first thing you have to do is install Node.js. You can do it by using following command in terminal:</p><p>cURL:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ curl https://raw.github.com/creationix/nvm/v0.33.11/install.sh | sh<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>Wget:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ wget -qO- https://raw.github.com/creationix/nvm/v0.33.11/install.sh | sh<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>After the installation is complete, restart the terminal and execute the following commands to install Node.js.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ nvm install stable<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>When it is finish then you can use npm to install Hexo.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ npm install -g hexo-cli<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><h3 id="Configure-Hexo"><a href="#Configure-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="Configure Hexo"></a>Configure Hexo</h3><p>When Hexo is finished installed, then you are prepared to build your own static website/blogg.<br>First create a empty folder:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">mkdir &lt;your_blog_name&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>then install Hexo into the folder<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">hexo init &lt;your_blog_name&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>Yeee, your website is created!!! Easy, right? Let move on!!!</p><hr><p>Attention: you maybe have to execute this command before you execute hexo.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash"><span class="hljs-built_in">source</span> ~/.nvm/nvm.sh<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><hr><p>Next thing you have to do is configure your website. After Hexo is install at your folder, you will se a document with name <code>_config.yml</code>. I know it looks complex but don’t give up. We will go through this document step by step and show how you configure your website. (I will be back)</p><h4 id="Hexo-Common-commands"><a href="#Hexo-Common-commands" class="headerlink" title="Hexo Common commands"></a>Hexo Common commands</h4><p>Here is some bacics command that you should know.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">hexo new “postName” / hexo n “postName”<span class="hljs-comment"># create new post</span><br>hexo clean <span class="hljs-comment"># clear cache</span><br>hexo generate / hexo g <span class="hljs-comment"># Generate static pages to the public directory</span><br>hexo server / hexo s <span class="hljs-comment"># Open preview access port</span><br>hexo deploy / hexo d <span class="hljs-comment"># deploy to GitHub(if you use GitHub)</span><br>hexo <span class="hljs-built_in">help</span> <span class="hljs-comment"># For help</span><br>hexo version <span class="hljs-comment"># check the version of hexo</span><br>-------<br><span class="hljs-comment"># You can also combine then is you want.</span><br>hexo s -g <span class="hljs-comment"># Server and generate</span><br>hexo d -g <span class="hljs-comment"># Generate and deploy</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><h3 id="Deploy-Hexo-at-GitHub"><a href="#Deploy-Hexo-at-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Deploy Hexo at GitHub"></a>Deploy Hexo at GitHub</h3><p>Above I showed you how to install hexo and create a website. Now you may want to publish it. To do it you have to deploy to GitHub first and install the deployment plugin. To install he deployment plugin you can do with following command:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ npm install hexo-deployer-git --save<br>$ npm install hexo-server --save<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>If you never used GitHub and git before then you must configure git. Like:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ git config --global user.name <span class="hljs-string">&quot;Your_user_name&quot;</span><br>$ git config --global user.email <span class="hljs-string">&quot;Your_email@example.com&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><p>Then you go back till<code>_config.yml</code> and you will find <code>deploy</code> below the document. Then filli<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">deploy:<br>  <span class="hljs-built_in">type</span>: git<br>  repo: &lt;repository url&gt;<br>  branch: master (main or master it depends)<br>  message:&lt;<span class="hljs-keyword">if</span> you want&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>When you are finish, then in the root directory of the local Hexo site, execute the following commands to deploy to GitHub:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash"><span class="hljs-built_in">source</span> ~/.nvm/nvm.sh (maybe)<br>$ hexo clean &amp;&amp; hexo d -g<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><p>Tadda, looks how easy it is. Now you publish your website successfully. There are few more things that I want to show you, first you may notice your website does not look beautiful. Hence the next step is how to change the theme so your blog looks more elegant. Second is about the domain name of your website. A great domain name makes more people remember your site and also gives your more confidence.</p><h3 id="Install-theme"><a href="#Install-theme" class="headerlink" title="Install theme"></a>Install theme</h3><p>I my case I use theme <a href="https://hexo.fluid-dev.com/docs/en/">fluid</a>. This is a Material Design style theme. In this <a href="https://hexo.io/themes/">link</a> you can find all themes for hexo, if you do not like fluid.<br><img src="/img/123favicon.png" alt=""><br><strong>Some functionality of fluid</strong></p><ul><li>Image lazy loading</li><li>Custom code highlighting scheme</li><li>Built-in multiple languages</li><li>Support multiple comment plugins</li><li>Support the use of data files to store configuration, smooth upgrade</li><li>Custom static resource CDN</li><li>Built-in article search</li><li>Footer filing information</li><li>Web page visit statistics</li><li>Supports LaTeX mathematical formulas (Oh year~)</li></ul><p>You can click this <a href="https://github.com/fluid-dev/hexo-theme-fluid/releases">link</a> to install theme fluid for the latest release version. After downloading, extract it to the <code>themes</code> directory and rename it to <code>fluid</code>. Then change <code>theme: fluid</code> in <code>_config.yml</code>. After that you have to create about site.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new page about<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>And then you will se a document at <code>/source/about/index.md</code> and add<code>layout</code>.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">title: about<br>date: <span class="hljs-string">&#x27;&#x27;</span><br>layout: about &lt;---- you need add it<br>---<br><br>Text here...<br>SupportsMarkdown, HTML<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>For more information about how to change the outlook, please have a look at the fluids website.</p><h3 id="About-domain-namn"><a href="#About-domain-namn" class="headerlink" title="About domain namn"></a>About domain namn</h3><p>I still did not fix domain namn for my blog…</p><p>To be continue…</p><h2 id="More-advance-about-Hexo"><a href="#More-advance-about-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="More advance about Hexo"></a>More advance about Hexo</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Git</tag>
      
      <tag>Blog</tag>
      
      <tag>Life</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
