<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>At my 19 years old, I started to play violin.</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/18/play_violin/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/18/play_violin/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Funktionsteorin</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/18/Funktionsteori/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/18/Funktionsteori/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Bakgrund"><a href="#Bakgrund" class="headerlink" title="Bakgrund"></a>Bakgrund</h3><p>Funktionsteorin så kallas även komplexa analys. Här är mina anteckningar från boken funktionsteorin av Frank Wikström. Det var en riktigt spännande bok som guida dig genom harmonisk analys och komplexa analys inom matematiken.</p><h3 id="1-Komplexa-funktioner"><a href="#1-Komplexa-funktioner" class="headerlink" title="1. Komplexa funktioner"></a>1. Komplexa funktioner</h3><p>Innan vi går vidare till derivator skall vi sätta ett definetion om gränsvärde för komlexa funktion. gränsvärde för komplexa funktioner har ungefär exakt samma pricip som den reellla funktion.</p><div class="note note-danger">            <p>Anta att $f$ är en komplexvärd funktion som är definera på någon omgivning av punkten $z = a$. Så gäller gränsvärde för komplexvärd funktion</p><p><center>$\lim_{z \to a}f(z) = L$</center><br>Om det finns till varje $\epsilon &gt; 0$ finns ett $\delta &gt; 0$ sådana att</p><p><center>$|f(z)-L| < \delta$</center><br>för alla z med 0 &lt; $|z-a|&lt;\delta$</p>          </div><p>De vanöiga relltvärdes gränsvärde räknelagar gäller även sammma för komplexvärda funktioner. Alltså</p><div class="note note-warning">            <p>Antar att $\lim<em>{z \to a}f(z) = L$ och $\lim</em>{z \to a}g(z) = M$ då $\lim_{z \to a}(f(z)+g(z)) = L+M$<br>Detta har motsvarande resonomang för substration, division och multipication.</p>          </div><h3 id="2-Elementara-funktioner"><a href="#2-Elementara-funktioner" class="headerlink" title="2. Elementära funktioner"></a>2. Elementära funktioner</h3><h3 id="3-Komplex-integralkalkyl"><a href="#3-Komplex-integralkalkyl" class="headerlink" title="3. Komplex integralkalkyl"></a>3. Komplex integralkalkyl</h3><h3 id="4-Talfoljder-och-rekursionsekvationer"><a href="#4-Talfoljder-och-rekursionsekvationer" class="headerlink" title="4. Talföljder och rekursionsekvationer"></a>4. Talföljder och rekursionsekvationer</h3>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>mathematics</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Some amazing site</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/17/file/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/17/file/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>What is the meaning of self-control?</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/16/What%20is%20meaning%20to%20be%20self-control/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/16/What%20is%20meaning%20to%20be%20self-control/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>life</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Who am I? where I come from? where I want to go?</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/16/Who%20am%20I/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/16/Who%20am%20I/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Who-am-I"><a href="#Who-am-I" class="headerlink" title="Who am I ?"></a>Who am I ?</h3><blockquote><p>“knowing yourself is the beginning of all wisdom.” -Aristotle</p><p>“knowing other is wisdom knowing the self is enlightenment” -Lao Tzu</p></blockquote><p>More than two thousand years ago, some people already began to think about self-consciousness. Aristoteles(384–322 BC) and Lao Tzu (600 BC) were the most famous ideologists and philosophers at the same period. The thing which surprised me is Lao Tzu came from Ancient China, meanwhile Aristoteles was från Ancient Greece and they both realized the importance of self-identity. Since these two independently developed civilizations can have such the same ideas. It really surprised me.  This kind of wisdom may not be truly understood by many people in today’s society. What I believe people nowadays pursue more material life than spirit of life.</p><h3 id="Where-I-come-from"><a href="#Where-I-come-from" class="headerlink" title="Where I come from?"></a>Where I come from?</h3><p>I know that is stupid quation. Everyone knows what themselves come from. Many people will say I am coming from some country or maybe they can specify where in the country in which city and road and so on. But do they really know where they </p><h3 id="Where-I-want-to-go"><a href="#Where-I-want-to-go" class="headerlink" title="Where I want to go?"></a>Where I want to go?</h3><blockquote><p>“I come from the great Tang dynasty of the east land and I’m going to pilgrim the budda for lection.” -Tang Sanzang</p></blockquote><p>This quote is coming from the chinese novel “Journey to the West”, it is one of the four great classical novels of chinese literature. This novel was published in the 16th century during the Ming dynasty and talked about the story of Tang Sanzang and his apprentices Sun Wukong, Zhu Bajie and Sha Wujing and going to the west to learn the scripture. Later it adapted from a novel into a TV series. As a child this was one of my favourite TV serier. I am atheist but this story really impacted me a lot.</p><p>This sentence is difficult to express its essence in other languages than chinese. It it little werid when I read it in english.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>life</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why I chose physics, Especially theoretical physics?</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/16/why%20just%20physics/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/16/why%20just%20physics/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I still don’t know why I chose physics from the beginig. It just feel coming from nowhere. I am not a genius at physics or something. What I actually remember from my early life was I like mathematics. I would not say I am the best but my mark in math is second to none in the class.</p><p>The first memory that I actually know about the concept physics is at junior high school. To be honest, in the three year i don’t even know that I had a physics teacher but this did not make me lose my interest in physics.</p><p>When I was in second grade at junior high school I readed “The Quantum World” by Kenneth W. Ford. This book makes me think about physics and what is the fundamental of this universe(Sorry Hawking, your book “brief history of time” was not inspiring enough). In this book, I was the first time I really realized how fascinating and beautiful this universe is. In that moment I also realized how ignorable we are to compare the whole universe. The main reason I like physics is it makes me think and be curious all the time. From that day I decided to work with physics like “quantum” stuff or “particle” stuff that even I did not really know what this is. I never was a genius in physics or something. Maybe in my age when I was a child that Albert Einstein already began to think about the universe and I was the little poor boy sitting down in the sandpit and playing in the sand.</p><p>When I was in the third year of junior high school, I was confused about choosing high school. Most of the people in my class choose a high school near home. In this case, I was the special case, I want to leave home, leave from my parents. It was a long story about this, I will take it up someday about why I had this though. I am very lucky and met my syv or school counselor. She was kind and helped me a lot with how to choose high school. So far I am still very grateful to her. Without her I may not be here, my physics passion may be gone, who knows. Finally, I had a choice for my high school, Polhemskolan, with orientation gift education in physics. Actually, I had no idea what this meant, but what I knew is my high school would not be bored and I will meet a lot of people with the same passion as me.</p><p>After I finished my Junior high school.</p><p>At High school, I studied in Polhemskolan with orientation gifted education at physics. This orientation is only found in Lund throughout Sweden. I am very proud for my-self of being able to study at this school. I learned a lot there, and met a lot of amazing people.<br><img src="/img/polhemc.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Now I am at Uppsala university a</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>why so many why!?</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>physics</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>What do I expect to learn during the three years at university</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/16/What%20I%20expect%20to%20learn%20during%20university/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/16/What%20I%20expect%20to%20learn%20during%20university/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>life</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>blog</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Endimentionell analys</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/16/Endimentionell%20analys/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/16/Endimentionell%20analys/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Instuderingsfrågor för Endimensionell analys</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-1"><a href="#Kapitel-1" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 1"></a>Kapitel 1</h3><p><strong>1. Vilka talmängder betecknas med N, Z, Q och R?</strong><br>N = naturliga talen; 1,2,3,4,5</p><p>Z = alla heltal; ..-2,-1,0,1,2..</p><p>Q = Rationella tal;  a/b där a och b ∈ Z != 0.</p><p>R = Reella tal; alla tal som finns i tallinjen.</p><p><strong>2. Vad betyder tecknen ∈, ⊆, ∅, ⇒ respektive ⇔?</strong></p><p><strong>3. Varför kan symbolerna ⇒ och ⇔ inte användas mellan två uttryck?</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-2"><a href="#Kapitel-2" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 2"></a>Kapitel 2</h3><p><strong>4. Hur adderas, multipliceras och divideras bråk?</strong></p><p><strong>5. Vad menas med kvadratkomplettering? Kan alla andragradspolynom, t.ex. även $x^2$, kvadratkompletteras?</strong></p><p><strong>6. Skriv upp formeln för polynomdivision, $f(x)\over g(x)$= . . ., och använd denna för att bevisa faktorsatsen.</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-P"><a href="#Kapitel-P" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel P"></a>Kapitel P</h3><p><strong>7. Vad är det för skillnad mellan ett axiom, en definition och en sats?</strong></p><p><strong>8. Vad menas med parallella linjer i planet?</strong><br><strong>9. Visa att vertikalvinklar är lika stora.</strong><br><strong>10. Formulera ett axiom som handlar om linjer och vinklar.</strong><br><strong>11. Vad menas med kongruenta trianglar? Formulera kongruensaxiomen.</strong><br><strong>12. Vad är vinkelsumman i en triangel respektive fyrhörning? Ge bevis.</strong><br><strong>13. Formulera och bevisa yttervinkelsatsen.</strong><br><strong>14. Definiera följande: cirkel, parallellogram, romb, parallelltrapets, rektangel och kvadrat.</strong><br><strong>15. Visa att varje rektangel är en parallellogram och att varje romb är en parallellogram.</strong><br><strong>16. Formulera och bevisa parallellogramsatsen.</strong><br><strong>17. Visa att diagonalerna i en parallellogram delar varandra mitt itu.</strong><br><strong>18. Formulera och bevisa satsen om en likbent triangel samt basvinkelsatsen.</strong><br><strong>19. Vad menas med en sluten polygon och hur kan man beräkna arean av området innanför en sådan?</strong></p><p><strong>20. Bevisa formler för triangelns, parallellogrammens samt parallelltrapetsets area.</strong><br><strong>21. Formulera och bevisa Pythagoras sats.</strong></p><p><strong>22. Om hypotenusan och en katet i en rätvinklig triangel är lika med motsvarande sidor i en annan, hur kan man då dra slutsatsen att de två trianglarna är kongruenta?</strong></p><p><strong>23. Formulera och bevisa omvändningen till Pythagoras sats. (Det finns ytterligare ett bevis bland övningarna. Välj själv det du tycker är enklast.)</strong><br><strong>24. Formulera transversalsatsen.</strong><br><strong>25. Vad menas med att två trianglar är likformiga?</strong><br><strong>26. Formulera topptriangelsatsen.</strong><br><strong>27. Formulera bisektrissatsen.</strong><br><strong>28. Formulera alla likformighetsfallen.</strong><br><strong>29. Formulera och bevisa randvinkelsatsen samt två omedelbara följder av denna.</strong><br><strong>30. Definiera en tangent till en cirkel och ange en viktig egenskap hos denna.</strong></p><h3 id="Kapitel-3"><a href="#Kapitel-3" class="headerlink" title="Kapitel 3"></a>Kapitel 3</h3><p><strong>31. Vad är skillnaden mellan en ekvation och ett uttryck? Ge exempel.</strong><br><strong>32. Vad menas med att två ekvationer är ekvivalenta?</strong><br><strong>33. Vad kan man göra med en ekvation, om man vill få en ny ekvivalent ekvation? Ge tre exempel på operationer där en ny ekvation uppstår, som inte säkert är ekvivalent med den ursprungliga.</strong><br><strong>34. Härled lösningsformeln för andragradsekvationen $x^2 + px + q = 0$.</strong><br><strong>35. Hur angriper du olikheter som innehåller polynom och kvoter av polynom?</strong></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Mathematics</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Experimental determination of the maximal lyapunov exponent of the magnetic pendulum</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/16/Experimental%20determination%20of%20the%20maximal%20lyapunov%20exponent%20of%20the%20manetic%20pendulum/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/16/Experimental%20determination%20of%20the%20maximal%20lyapunov%20exponent%20of%20the%20manetic%20pendulum/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="note note-primary">            <p><strong>Abstract:</strong></p><p>The magnetic pendulum has a simple structure but a complex chaotic behaviour. Since a system has a positive maximal lyapunov exponent is strong indicates that system is chaotic. The studies of magnetic pendulum have been mathematically and numerically understood. Unfortunately, it is still lack of experimental examination of the lyapunov exponent of magnetic pendulum due the extreme and sensitive requirement. In this project is studied about the maximal lyapunov of magnetic pendulum experimentally. The study is not extensive and specifics for the chaotic behavior of magnetic pendulum. However, the result are showed the magnetic pendulum has a positive maximal lyapunov exponent about 28 1/s with a given parameter. Which is strong indicates that magnetic pendulum has a chaotic behaviour.</p>          </div>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>physics</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>GitHub + Latex make more efficient for writing and collaboration</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/16/GitHub%20+%20Latex%20make%20more%20efficient%20for%20writing%20and%20collaboration/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/16/GitHub%20+%20Latex%20make%20more%20efficient%20for%20writing%20and%20collaboration/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Camputer things</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Coming to Sweden was a turning point in my life</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/16/Coming%20to%20Sweden%20was%20a%20turning%20point%20in%20my%20life/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/16/Coming%20to%20Sweden%20was%20a%20turning%20point%20in%20my%20life/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I still remember that in October 2010, it was a snowy night that I set foot on the land of Sweden. What a beautiful country, that I never seen before. Especially it snowing that night. I was curious because I have never seen snow where I used to live in my homeland.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>My story</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>My story</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>From zero to 1, how to create your own blog</title>
    <link href="/2020/12/14/My%20first%20blog%20and%20why/"/>
    <url>/2020/12/14/My%20first%20blog%20and%20why/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/blog2.jpg" alt=""></p><h2 id="Background"><a href="#Background" class="headerlink" title="Background"></a>Background</h2><h3 id="Why-I-want-strart-writing-blog"><a href="#Why-I-want-strart-writing-blog" class="headerlink" title="Why I want strart writing blog"></a>Why I want strart writing blog</h3><p>Creating a blog was an idea I had in few weeks ago. I tried many times before and after but all ended in failure. Recently, my idea of creating a blog has become stronger and stronger. Accidently I found out that I can create my own blog by using GitHub. And there is what you see now.</p><p>Before I was a person who relied heavily on social media. Every time I turn on the phone, the first thing I do is watch video,  post and check what others have done aimlessly. At that moment I don’t feel my-self. In this era of “information explosion”, I found slowly that I became unable to think independently. So I gradually stay away from various social media such as Facebook, WeChat, QQ, etc. The main reason why I stay away from them is very simple because they give me innutritious information all the time.</p><p>I hope that in this blog I can quietly be my-self and write down my true feelings. Here I hope I can think freely, without considering other people’s feelings. This is also my original intention of creating this blog. In addition, I also want to record every moment of this young man, after all you are still worth remembering in this rushed world. Whenever this young man wants to look back, at least there are stories that belong to him, and some of his whimsical thoughts.</p><p>  2020-12-14</p><p>  Z.H.</p><h2 id="How-to-create-a-blog-using-GitHub-and-Hexo"><a href="#How-to-create-a-blog-using-GitHub-and-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="How to create a blog using GitHub and Hexo"></a>How to create a blog using GitHub and Hexo</h2><p>In this page I gonna introduce how to use Github and Hexo to build your own static website or blog. Attention, all the install here is based on operatingsystem Linux disto <code>Ubuntu 20.04.1</code>. Let’s go it will be fun and fun :D.</p><h2 id="GitHub"><a href="#GitHub" class="headerlink" title="GitHub"></a>GitHub</h2><h3 id="Short-intro-about-GitHub-and-why-GitHub"><a href="#Short-intro-about-GitHub-and-why-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Short intro about GitHub and why GitHub"></a>Short intro about GitHub and why GitHub</h3><p>If you never use GitHub before then to <a href="https://github.com/">https://github.com/</a> and create an account. There are some avantage to build a blog.</p><ul><li>It is totally free and convenient.</li><li>Due the static file, it has fast access speed.</li><li>GitHub has versioncontrol functionality. Hence your data of each version of your blog is safe and you can restore it if you want.</li><li>You can do and design whatever you want.</li></ul><h3 id="Create-a-repository-at-GitHub"><a href="#Create-a-repository-at-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Create a repository at GitHub"></a>Create a repository at GitHub</h3><p>Loggin at GitHub and click <code>New repository</code>. Here you must pay attention that your name of repository must be <code>&#39;your username&#39;.github.io</code>. Otherwises it would not work. I mean it still work..but not enough elegant.</p><h2 id="Hexo"><a href="#Hexo" class="headerlink" title="Hexo"></a>Hexo</h2><h3 id="What-is-Hexo-and-why-you-need-it"><a href="#What-is-Hexo-and-why-you-need-it" class="headerlink" title="What is Hexo and why you need it?"></a>What is Hexo and why you need it?</h3><p>Basically Hexo is a blog framework that allows you to quickly build a blog. In my case I chose Hexo because it is fast, concise and efficient. Hexo is written by Node.js and it also supports Markdown and many other packages. Hence you actually don’t need that much programming och computer knowledge like HTML、css、JavaScript etc. The only thing you should learn or feel familiar with is Markdown. Of course if you want your blog to look prefekt and beautiful that is strong recommend that you master the basics programming language like HTML.</p><h3 id="Install-Hexo"><a href="#Install-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="Install Hexo"></a>Install Hexo</h3><p>This installation is based on operating system Linux distro Ubuntu. The first thing you have to do is install Node.js. You can do it by using following command in terminal:</p><p>cURL:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ curl https://raw.github.com/creationix/nvm/v0.33.11/install.sh | sh<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>Wget:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ wget -qO- https://raw.github.com/creationix/nvm/v0.33.11/install.sh | sh<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>After the installation is complete, restart the terminal and execute the following commands to install Node.js.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ nvm install stable<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>When it is finish then you can use npm to install Hexo.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ npm install -g hexo-cli<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><h3 id="Configure-Hexo"><a href="#Configure-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="Configure Hexo"></a>Configure Hexo</h3><p>When Hexo is finished installed, then you are prepared to build your own static website/blogg.<br>First create a empty folder:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">mkdir &lt;your_blog_name&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>then install Hexo into the folder<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">hexo init &lt;your_blog_name&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>Yeee, your website is created!!! Easy, right? Let move on!!!</p><hr><p>Attention: you maybe have to execute this command before you execute hexo.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash"><span class="hljs-built_in">source</span> ~/.nvm/nvm.sh<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><hr><p>Next thing you have to do is configure your website. After Hexo is install at your folder, you will se a document with name <code>_config.yml</code>. I know it looks complex but don’t give up. We will go through this document step by step and show how you configure your website. (I will be back)</p><h4 id="Hexo-Common-commands"><a href="#Hexo-Common-commands" class="headerlink" title="Hexo Common commands"></a>Hexo Common commands</h4><p>Here is some bacics command that you should know.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">hexo new “postName” / hexo n “postName”<span class="hljs-comment"># create new post</span><br>hexo clean <span class="hljs-comment"># clear cache</span><br>hexo generate / hexo g <span class="hljs-comment"># Generate static pages to the public directory</span><br>hexo server / hexo s <span class="hljs-comment"># Open preview access port</span><br>hexo deploy / hexo d <span class="hljs-comment"># deploy to GitHub(if you use GitHub)</span><br>hexo <span class="hljs-built_in">help</span> <span class="hljs-comment"># For help</span><br>hexo version <span class="hljs-comment"># check the version of hexo</span><br>-------<br><span class="hljs-comment"># You can also combine then is you want.</span><br>hexo s -g <span class="hljs-comment"># Server and generate</span><br>hexo d -g <span class="hljs-comment"># Generate and deploy</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><h3 id="Deploy-Hexo-at-GitHub"><a href="#Deploy-Hexo-at-GitHub" class="headerlink" title="Deploy Hexo at GitHub"></a>Deploy Hexo at GitHub</h3><p>Above I showed you how to install hexo and create a website. Now you may want to publish it. To do it you have to deploy to GitHub first and install the deployment plugin. To install he deployment plugin you can do with following command:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ npm install hexo-deployer-git --save<br>$ npm install hexo-server --save<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>If you never used GitHub and git before then you must configure git. Like:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ git config --global user.name <span class="hljs-string">&quot;Your_user_name&quot;</span><br>$ git config --global user.email <span class="hljs-string">&quot;Your_email@example.com&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><p>Then you go back till<code>_config.yml</code> and you will find <code>deploy</code> below the document. Then filli<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">deploy:<br>  <span class="hljs-built_in">type</span>: git<br>  repo: &lt;repository url&gt;<br>  branch: master (main or master it depends)<br>  message:&lt;<span class="hljs-keyword">if</span> you want&gt;<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>When you are finish, then in the root directory of the local Hexo site, execute the following commands to deploy to GitHub:<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash"><span class="hljs-built_in">source</span> ~/.nvm/nvm.sh (maybe)<br>$ hexo clean &amp;&amp; hexo d -g<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure></p><p>Tadda, looks how easy it is. Now you publish your website successfully. There are few more things that I want to show you, first you may notice your website does not look beautiful. Hence the next step is how to change the theme so your blog looks more elegant. Second is about the domain name of your website. A great domain name makes more people remember your site and also gives your more confidence.</p><h3 id="Install-theme"><a href="#Install-theme" class="headerlink" title="Install theme"></a>Install theme</h3><p>I my case I use theme <a href="https://hexo.fluid-dev.com/docs/en/">fluid</a>. This is a Material Design style theme. In this <a href="https://hexo.io/themes/">link</a> you can find all themes for hexo, if you do not like fluid.<br><img src="/img/123favicon.png" alt=""><br><strong>Some functionality of fluid</strong></p><ul><li>Image lazy loading</li><li>Custom code highlighting scheme</li><li>Built-in multiple languages</li><li>Support multiple comment plugins</li><li>Support the use of data files to store configuration, smooth upgrade</li><li>Custom static resource CDN</li><li>Built-in article search</li><li>Footer filing information</li><li>Web page visit statistics</li><li>Supports LaTeX mathematical formulas (Oh year~)</li></ul><p>You can click this <a href="https://github.com/fluid-dev/hexo-theme-fluid/releases">link</a> to install theme fluid for the latest release version. After downloading, extract it to the <code>themes</code> directory and rename it to <code>fluid</code>. Then change <code>theme: fluid</code> in <code>_config.yml</code>. After that you have to create about site.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new page about<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>And then you will se a document at <code>/source/about/index.md</code> and add<code>layout</code>.<br><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">title: about<br>date: <span class="hljs-string">&#x27;&#x27;</span><br>layout: about &lt;---- you need add it<br>---<br><br>Text here...<br>SupportsMarkdown, HTML<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><br>For more information about how to change the outlook, please have a look at the fluids website.</p><h3 id="About-domain-namn"><a href="#About-domain-namn" class="headerlink" title="About domain namn"></a>About domain namn</h3><p>I still did not fix domain namn for my blog…</p><p>To be continue…</p><h2 id="More-advance-about-Hexo"><a href="#More-advance-about-Hexo" class="headerlink" title="More advance about Hexo"></a>More advance about Hexo</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>blog</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
